Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, automation, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

Work History

2021-10 -Current

Senior Software Python Developer

PRNCORP-IT, Piscataway, NJ

- Drives application development focused around delivering business valuable features using cloud AWS infrastructure such as Lambdas ECS,EC2,API Gateways,Kinesis,SQS.
- Mentor and assist software engineers, providing technical assistance and direction as needed
- Support the design, build, and maintenance of Infrastructure on all AWS environment.
- Set up tracking and monitoring services such as AWS CloudTrail, CloudWatch Alarms, Centralized Logging, Notification and AWS Configin an effort to optimize cost and enforce compliance.
- Delivered unit-tested systems with required characteristics, covering edge cases and within customer-prescribed timeframes.

2019-10 -2021-10

Software Engineer(BackEnd)

Cummins Inc., Indianapolis, IN

- Analyze requirements and design, develop and implement software applications for multiple products.
- Drive automation and self-service throughout the Agile/DevOps development process.
- Designing and building application using cloud services such as (but not limited to) EC2, RDS, SNS, Kinesis fire-hose, VPC, S3, DynamoDB, API-Gateway, AWS Lambda, SQS and ECS, etc.
- Develop software solutions by studying information needs; conferring with users; studying systems flow,

VICTOR OLADOSU

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Dallas, TX, 75206

Phone

(361) 228-2991

E-mail

victoroladosu090@gmail.co m

Skills

Scripting(Bash,XML, Powershell, Python, Javascript, YAML,PGSQL)

Database management

Very Good

CI/CD (Jenkins, AWS code build and pipeline)

Excellent

Cloud security

Very Good

Agile workflow processes

Excellent

Portable code writer

Very Good

Algorithm implementation

Excellent

A/B testing

data usage and work processes; investigating problem areas; following the software development lifecycle; Document and demonstrate solutions; Develops flow charts, layouts and documentation.

 Performed user account maintenance tasks, archiving defunct credentials and monitoring login systems for suspicious trends.

2017-09 -2019-09

Graduate Assistant

Texas A&m University, Commerce, TX

- Designed and implemented system security and data assurance for the department.
- Wrote and maintained custom scripts to increase system efficiency and performance time.
- Saved \$100,000 by implementing cost-saving initiatives that addressed long-standing problems.
- Implemented network security equipment, including firewalls, two-factor authentication, and antivirus software for networks supporting 120 users.
- Designed, modified, developed, wrote and implemented software programming applications.
- Defined applications and their interfaces, allocated responsibilities to applications, understood solution deployment, and communicated requirements for interactions with solution context, defined Nonfunctional Requirements (NFRs)

2014-11 -2017-09

Software Developer

JUMIA, Lagos, LA

- Delivered and maintained scalable system architecture to support high-availability
 E-COMMERCE site with various internal applications.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Pioneered new methods of code review to incorporate wider range of voices, enhancing final products with ideas otherwise overlooked.
- Revised, modularized and updated legacy code bases to modern development standards and best practices, reducing operating costs by 40%.
- Conducted regression testing on applications about

- to ship to production and, analyzed results and submitted observations to development team lead.
- Tested troubleshooting methods, devised innovative solutions, and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team use.
- Supported software integration and implemented maintenance enhancements to bolster product development cycle.

Education

2017-05 -2020-05 Master of Science: Business Analytics

Texas A&M University - Commerce - Commerce, TX